Arthur Lyu

Software Developer

Summary

A certified .Net developer with many years of experience working in IT, with last 8 years working primarily with Microsoft technologies helping enterprises to achieve their business goals, improve productivity and add extra value to their customers. I am passionate about IT, enjoy learning new things and keeping up to date with the latest technologies.

Summary of Skills and Attributes

I have been using many technologies such as:

- ASP.NET, .Net Core, Azure, Docker, C#, MVC, Entity framework, Message Queue, Rest API, Xamarin forms and SQL Server Database.
- Version control tool DevOps, CI, CD and GitHub, and working in Agile (Scrum) environment.
- OOP, functional program design patterns and SOLID conception.
- Balzor(server-side and web assembly), jQuery, JavaScript, Angular, Bootstrap, CSS and HTML.
- Testing tool XUnit, SpecFlow, Selenium.

Industry experience:

- Supply Chain Collaboration systems.
- Inventory management systems
- Freight quote systems
- Hire to purchase systems
- Online shopping websites

Education

Jilin University, China, 2006

Master of Software Engineering

Jilin University, China, 2000

Major in Applications Development

Certifications

- 2020, Azure Fundamentals. Azure Developer Associate.
- 2015, Microsoft Certified Professional of ASP.NET Web Applications & Programming in C# Professional
- 2006, Training of BEA WEBLOGIC Application & Developing
- 2004, Training Microsoft Project Manager

Career Experience

LPS New Zealand Limited Software Engineer September 2018 – Present

Client: Kotahi Software Engineer September 2018 – July 2020

Responsibilities:

- Support TMS team and System Acceptance Testing Team of Kotahi New Zealand as a Software Engineer.
- Use relevant techniques and develop tools to perform code optimizations and reviews to assure system quality.
- Work under Azure development environment and use Microsoft technologies like DevOps,CI, CD, Microservice, Rest API and so on.
- Attend daily standup, refinement, retro meetings, sprint review and plan meetings to better track and deliver high quality testing solutions.
- Create unit, integration, component, system and end to end tests to complete sprint plan tasks to assure performant and sound technical delivery of the most crucial Testing Team in the company.

Achievements:

- In order to increase testing performance, develop the order generator tool by using blazor web assembly, REST API and Seleniums to simplify and automate daily testing works.
- Develop the code repositories monitor to track unit, integration and code line changes for managers. Setup the Sonarqube environment to help the team to optimize code quality.
- Complete sprint plan tasks that are assigned to me.

Unleashed (http://unleashedsoftware.com)
.Net Software Developer
May 2016 – August 2018

2.6K+ online customers around the world 70 staff, offices in the UK, Australia, USA and NZ.

Responsibilities:

- Work as a full stack developer. The techniques that I have been using are ASP.NET, .NET
 Core, C#, REST API, SQL Database, NOSQL Database, Message queue, Service Bus, Azure,
 AWS, CI, CD for back-end and MVC, Angular, Angular JS, JQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS
 and HTML for front-end.
- Cooperate with team members like project Scrum managers, product owner, Quality Assurance and other developers to accomplish tasks.
- Based on designs and product owner requirements, translate application storyboards and use cases into functional applications
- Attend daily stand-up, sprint plan meetings and knowledge sharing meetings, and provide stable and professional solutions.
- Design, build, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable C# code. Also ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications
- Daily maintenance use troubleshooting skills to identify bottlenecks and bugs, and create datafix or codefix to solve those problems

Achievements:

- Utilize asp.net, C# and relevant techniques to maintain and optimize our current inventory application.
- Enhance our third party integration APIs with our system and those APIs are like accounting system Xero and QBO, and other commercial websites APIs like Shopify, Amazon, Vend and Magento.

Manchester & More .Net Software Developer September 2014 – March 2015

Thousands of customers around the world, office in NZ and Australia

Responsibilities:

- The techniques that I used is ASP.NET Framework 4.5, SQL Server 2012, Entity Framework 6, C#, REST APIs (Web API 2), Xamarin.Form, MVC 5, JavaScript, jQuery, JQueryUI, JSON, Bootstrap 3, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3 and AJAX.
- Based on requirements, I had been responsible for developing a customized inventory management software and smart phone application.
- Attend requirement meeting and provide professional solutions.

Achievements:

- A new inventory management system and commercial products website.
- Develop Android and IOS applications for inventory managers.

GoSweetSpot (http://gosweetspot.com)
.Net Software Developer
March 2014 – September 2014

Over 2000 businesses around the world. The largest courier and freight aggregator in NZ. Office in NZ.

Responsibilities:

- Based on the senior developers' designs and original requirements and use C#, MVC, SQL Database, REST API and relevant techniques like JQuery, bootstrap, HTML and CSS to develop applications.
- Attend requirement meetings and provide stable and practical solutions.

Achievements:

- A new quoting application.
- Integrate eBay and Unleashed API with our management system.
- A new smartphone application running android, iOS and Windows phone operations for the parcel track system.

ishoppers

.Net Software Developer August 2013 – February 2014

Responsibilities:

- Use Microsoft technologies like ASP.NET, MVC, C#, Azure, SQL Server Database, JQuery, bootstrap, HTML and CSS to do development.
- Responsible for design and coding.

• Participate in business meetings and, based on customer's requirements, I was responsible for offering professional solutions.

Achievements:

- A new hire to purchase management system for Goodvalue and APlusHamper Companies.
- A new online trade application named ishopper shopping.

Bargain Hunting
.Net Software Developer
November 2011 – February 2013

Responsibilities:

- Use Microsoft technologies like ASP.NET, MVC, C#, Azure, SQL Server Database, JQuery, bootstrap, HTML and CSS to do development.
- Responsible for design and coding to build new functions for Buz and NetSky.
- Attend requirement meetings and provide professional solutions.
- Maintain an existing website application.

Achievements:

- Completed the existing website named Bargainhunting.
- A new social network website named Buz.

Project Experience

- 2016-2018 Maintaining and optimizing Unleashed company inventory system.
- 2015 Inventory management system for Manchester & More Company
- 2014 2014.9: Freight quoting system, integrating eBay and unleashed API with our current system and parcel track phone application.
- 2013 2014: Hire to purchase management system for two companies and online trade website. ishoppers clothing shopping, vineyard wine sale website.
- 2011-2012: NetSky, Buz (social network website) and Bargain Hunt website (online trade website)